Edward Northup Hay Papers 5227
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Series V. Publications
  - "The Application of Weber's Law to Job Evaluation Estimates", 1950 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    Journal of Applied Psychology, Vol. 34, No. 2, April, 1950. pp. 102-104
  - "Prediction from Selected Cutting Scores.", 1949 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    (mimeographed) June, 1949. 14 pp
  - "Setting Standards of Value for Executive Compensation", 1949 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    The Controller, March, 1949. pp. 116-118.
  - A Flexible Method of Salary Cost Control, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    New York: American Management Association. 8 pp
  - "Creating Factor Comparison Key Scales by the Per Cent Method", 1948 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    Journal of Applied Psychology, Vol. 32, No. 5, October, 1948. pp. 456-464
  - "Cross Validation of Clerical Aptitude Tests", 1950 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    Journal of Applied Psychology, Vol. 34, No. 3, June, 1950. pp. 153-158
  - Your Pay, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    Philadelphia: Edward N. Hay Associates. 13 pp
  - "A Note on Small Samples", 1953 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    Journal of Applied Psychology, Vol. 37, No. 6, December, 1953. p. 445
  - "The Validation of Tests", 1953 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    Personnel, May, 1953. 10 pp
  - "What Should a Personnel Department be Doing", 1953 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    Personnel Panorama, Vol. 6, No. 1, January, 1953. 3 pp
  - "Validation of Tests.", 1952 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    (mimeographed) October, 1952. 7 pp
  - "How You Administer Salaries Goes Deep", 1951 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    Management Review, May, 1951. p. 271.
  - "Some Research Findings with the Wonderlic Personnel Test", 1952 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    Journal of Applied Psychology, Vol. 36, No. 5, October, 1952. pp. 344-345
  - "The Analysis and Description of High-Level Jobs", 1953 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    Personnel, January, 1953. 12 pp
  - "Reviewing Expense Accounts: A Study in Character", 1952 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    Management Review, July, 1952. pp. 455-456
  - "Banks, No Less Than Industry Have Communications Problems", 1952 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    Bankers Monthly, April, 1952. p. 38+
  - "The Profile Method of High-Level Job Evaluation", 1951 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    Personnel, Vol. 28, No. 2, 1951. 11 pp
  - "Aptitude Tests Reduce Operating Costs.", 1951 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    (unpublished) 6 p
  - "Investigation of the Use of Tests as a Predictor of Leadership and Group Effectiveness in a Job Evaluation Situation", 1953 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    Journal of Social Psychology, Vol. 38, 1953. pp. 109-119
  - "Predicting Success in Routine Bank Work", 1951 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    Banking, June, 1951. 2 pp
  - "Prediction of Clerical Success in a Life Insurance Company - 1951." (Box 5, Folder 30)
    (mimeographed) May, 1951. 4 pp
  - "Validating Clerical Tests in a Branch Bank.", 1951 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    (mimeographed) April, 1951. 2 pp
  - "Efficiency of Bank Bookkeeping Departments.", 1951 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - "Mental Ability Tests in Clerical Selection", 1951 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    Journal of Applied Psychology, Vol. 35, No. 4, August, 1951. pp. 250-251
  - Analysis and Evaluation of Executive Positions, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    Berkeley: California Personnel Management Association. 12 pp
  - "The Bethel Way of Acquiring Group Skills", 1956 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    Personnel Journal, Vol. 35, No. 5, October, 1956. pp. 178-181
  - "Some Problems Faced by Corporation Executives in Connection with Executive Salaries.", 1957 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    (draft for Harvard Business Review) January, 1957. 11 pp
  - "Something Has Been Done About Developing Salary Standards for Executive Positions.", 1957 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    (mimeographed) April, 1957. 8 pp
  - "Overtime Pay for Engineers", 1957 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    Personnel Journal, Vol. 36, No. 3, August, 1957. pp. 90-92.
  - "A Simple Method of Recording Paired Comparisons", 1958 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    Journal of Applied Psychology, Vol. 42, No. 2, 1958. pp. 139-140
  - "Civil Liberties Union Shadow-Boxes on Compulsory Unionism", 1956 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    Foreman's Digest, August, 1956. pp. 17-19
  - The Guide Chart-Profile Method of Job-Man Evaluation, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    New York: American Management Association, 8 pp
  - "Employee Relations in England", 1956 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    Personnel Journal, Vol. 35, No. 1, May, 1956. pp. 16-20
  - "Good Salary Administration.", 1956 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    (mimeographed) May, 1956. 7 pp.
  - "Effective Salary Administration.", 1956 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    (mimeographed) March, 1956. 4 pp.
  - "A New Method of Job Evaluation", 1954 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    Personnel, July, 1954. 11 pp
  - "Comparative Validities in Clerical Testing", 1954 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    Journal of Applied Psychology, Vol. 38, No. 5, 1954. pp. 291-301
  - "Bank Salary Administration for Employees and Officers.", 1956 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    (mimeographed) 8 pp
  - "Your Boss is Your Training Director", 1956 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    Personnel Journal, Vol. 35, No. 6, November, 1956. pp. 220-221
  - "Cutting Correspondence Costs" (Box 5, Folder 32)
    American Business, 5pp
  - "Predicting Success in Routine Bank Work." (Box 5, Folder 32)
    (unpublished), 9 pp
  - Current Problems in Wage and Salary Administration. (Box 5, Folder 32)
    Berkeley: California Personnel Management Association, no date. 7 pp.
  - "The Guide Chart-Profile Method: An Explanation." (Box 5, Folder 32)
    (mimeographed), 10 pp.
  - "Three Studies in Intra-Group Rating." (Box 5, Folder 32)
    (unpublished), 15 pp
  - "Do You Need a Systems and Procedures Section?" (Box 5, Folder 32)
    (unpublished), 6 pp
  - "Job Evaluation Reliability." (Box 5, Folder 32)
    (mimeographed), 13 pp
  - "Practical Rating Plans" (Box 5, Folder 32)
    (unknown publication), pp. 17-29
  - "A Battery of Tests for Clerical Aptitude." (Box 5, Folder 32)
    (unpublished), 16 pp
  - "Some Overlooked Responsibilities of Management Toward Employees." (Box 5, Folder 32)
    (mimeographed), 9 pp